Guide to the Stanford University Postcard Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Postcards (individual)
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 423; Color Print
    Caption: 204 - Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
    Image has a white border
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 424; Color Print
    Caption: C1125 - Stanford Chapel. Palo Alto, California: World-famous for it mosaic work is this beautiful chapel on the grounds of rhe Stanford University. The university was founded by Senator and Mrs. Leland Stanford in memory of their son and opened in 1891.
    Imprint: Mike Roberts Studios
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 425; Color Print
    Caption: C1125 - Stanford Chapel, Palo Alto, California: World-famous for its mosaic work in this beautiful chapel on the grounds of the Stanford University. The university was founded by Senator and Mrs. Leland Stanford in memory of their son and opened in 1891.
    Imprint: R. & C. Hakanson/Mike Roberts
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 426; Color Print
    Caption: 435 - The Memorial Church, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California
    additional caption on back: "Stanford Memorial Chapel -- located on the Campus of Stanford University, is considered one of the most beautiful churches in America..."
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 427; Color Print
    Caption: PA7: -- Memorial Church, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 428; Color Print
    Caption: 6741 - Stanford Memorial Chapel, Palo Alto, California
    additional caption on back: "Stanford Memorial Chapel is one of the picturesque spots on the large campus of the Leland Stanford Unviversity. It's beautiful mosaics on the facade of the church and within its walls are greatly admired by travellers from all over the world."
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 429; Color Print
    Caption: 5 - Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 430; B/W Print
    Caption: 259 - Memorial Church, Stanford University
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 431; B/W Print
    Caption: Memorial Church, Stanford University, Calif.
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 432; Color Print
    Caption: No. 43 - Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
    Imprint: The Albertype Co. for Stanford Book Store
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 433; Color Print
    Caption: #903 - Stanford Memorial Church, Stanford University, Photographer - John Wagner
    Imprint: Impact
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 434; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church: Through Memorial Arch
    Imprint: Stanford University Press
    Stamped on back: "Stanford University Press Library"
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, 867; B/W Print
  - Memorial Church (Exterior) post 1906, post 1906, 2016-007.1 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 435; Color Print
    Caption: 416 - Interior Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 436; Color Print
    Caption: West Aisle and Clear Story, Stanford Memorial Church, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 437; B/W Print
    Caption: West Side of Nave, Stanford Memorial Church, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 438; B/W Print
    Caption: 5080 - Interior Memorial Chapel looking south, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 439; Color Print
    Caption: No. 34 - One of Center Arches, Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 440; Sepia Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church, Palo Alto, California
    One of the Center Arches. It is 65 feet from Floor to the under side of the Arch. Copyrighted No. 27
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 441; Color Print
    Caption: 428 - Interior, Memorial Church, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California
    Imprint: Stanley A Piltz
    additional caption on back: "Memorial Church, Stanford University, built as a memorial by Mrs. Stanford to her husband, Leland Stanford..."
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 442; Color Print
    Caption: 194 - Palo Alto, California, Interior Stanford Memorial Chapel
  - Memorial Church (Interior), 1906; 443; B/W Print
    Caption: 6111 - Interior View Memorial Church, Showing Chancel, Stanford University, Cal.
    Message: Palo Alto, Sunday May 20, 06. Card Marina (Check) is the same (illegible) after the (illegible) H.L.C.
    addressed to: Miss Pearl Chinny (?) Marion, Ohio
    postmark: May 21 11 AM 1906 from Palo Alto, Cal.
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 444; Color Print
    Caption: Chancel with Pulpit, Stanford Memorial Church, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 445; B/W Print
    Caption: 7 - The Chancel, Stanford University
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 446; Color Print
    Caption: Chancel with Altar, Stanford Memorial Church, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 447; Photo
    Caption: "Interior of Stanford University" Palo Alto
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 448; B/W Print
    Caption: The Chancel, Stanford Memorial Church. California
    Imprint: The Albertype Co. For Hyde's Book Store
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 449; Tinted Print
    Caption: 11 - The Chancel, Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), post 1906; 450; B/W Print
    Caption: 4276 - Interior Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), post 1906; 451; Color Print
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 452; Color Print
    Caption: 417 - Interior Memorial Chapel Showing Chancel, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 453; Color Print
    Caption: 417 - The Apse, Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 454; B/W Print
    Caption: 5081 - Interior Memorial Chapel Showing Chancel, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 455; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford Chapel, Stanford University, Stanford, Calif: This interior view of the famous Stanford Chapel shows the impressive architectural beauty of the structure. The mosaic work is outstanding.
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 456; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church: Interior View
    stamp: Stanford University Press Library
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 457; Sepia Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church, Palo Alto, Cal.
    "The Seraphs' Choir" or The Glory of the Angels Around the Altar. "In Mosaic." No. 34
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 458; Sepia Print
    Organ and Choir Loft
    No. 37
    note on back: facing back from the (illegible)
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 459; B/W Print
    Caption: Nave and Organ Loft, Stanford Memorial Church, California.
    note on back: Memorial Church -- nave and organ loft
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 460; Sepia Print
    The Nave from Vestibule looking toward Altar.
    No. 16
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 461; Color Print
    Caption: PA1: - Interior of Memorial Church, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 462; Sepia Print
    Dome fo the Church and East Gallery from the West Gallery.
    No. 36
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 463; Tinted Print
    Caption: No. 44 - The Chancel, Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 464; B/W Print
    Caption: Interior of the Memorial Church, Stanford University
    Imprint: Bardell for John M. Yanicks
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 465; B/W Print
    Caption: 150 - Interior of Memorial Church, Stanford University, Cal.
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 466; Sepia Print
    The Apostles are Presented "in Mosaic" above "The Seraphs' Choir."
    No. 35
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 467; Sepia Print
    "The Seraphs' Choir" or The Glory of the Angels Around the Altar. "In Mosaic."
    No. 34
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 468; Color Print
    Caption: 6743 - Mosaics, Stanford Memorial Chapel, Palo Alto, California.
    addition caption: Stanford Memorial Chapel -- The mosaics were brought from Italy by the late Leland Stanford and placed in position by skilled Italian craftsmen. The coloring is gorgeous and blends with the beautiful carved stonework and the exquisite colored windows.
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 469; Photo
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 470; Photo
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 471; B/W Print
    Caption: The Pulpit, Stanford Memorial Church, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 472; B/W Print
    Caption: 6 - The Pulpit, Stanford University.
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 473; Color Print
    Caption: Figures and Mosaics in Aspe E. Stanford Memorial Church, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 474; Sepia Print
    Caption: 26 - Stanford Memorial Church, Palo Alto, Calif.
    Art Windows Portraying Biblical Scenes are in Harmony with the Mosaic.
  - Memorial Church (Interior), 1904; 475; B/W Print
    Caption: 7290 - Interior of Memorial Church
    Message: Palo Alto: The men here are swell. Am having a grand time. Polly
    addressed to: Mr. Louis A. Goetz, 1854 Vallejo Street, San Francsico, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 476; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church, Altar Mosaic
    Stamp: Stanford University Press Library
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 477; B/W Print
    The "Last Supper" from the Sistine Chapel in the Vatican at Rome. The only Reproduction where Judas is represented with the Devil on his Shoulder. "In Mosaic."
    No. 33
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 478; B/W Print
    Caption: The Lord's Supper, Stanford Memorial Church, California
    Memorial Church - Lord's Supper
    stamp: Stanford University Libraries, Nov 27, 1942
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 479; Tinted Print
    Caption: The Lord's Supper, Memorial Church, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 480; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church, Sermon on the Mount
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 481; Sepia Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church, Palo Alto, Calif
    Garden of Eden. "In Mosaic."
    NO. 20
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 482; Sepia Print
    Caption: Stanford Memorial Church, Palo Alto, Calif.
    "Rachel Sees Jacob Approaching"
    "In Mosaic."
    No. 24
  - Memorial Church (Interior), Undated; 483; Sepia Print
    Florentine Mosaic Decoration over Byzantine Arches at Main Entrance
    No. 10
  - Memorial Court, post 1906; 484; Photo
    steel frame of Mem Chu visible in background; gift of Dir. of Info. 3/1/55
    Memorial Court
  - Memorial Court, Undated; 485; Sepia Print
    Caption: 1908 - Memorial Court, through the Arches, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Court, 1934; 486; B/W Print
    Caption: 1908 - Memorial Court, throught the Arches, Stanford University, California
  - Memorial Court, Undated; 487; Photo
    Caption: A Stanford University Arcade
  - Memorial Court, 1906; 488; Color Print
    Caption: 520 - The Court and Memorial Chapel, Stanford University, Palo Alto, Cal.
    addressed to: Mr. J. S. Cady, Sonora, (illegible) (illegible), Calif.
    postmark: Jan 6, 6-PM, 1906 from San Francisco, Cal
    other postmark: Jan 5, from Sonora
    note: glitter is glued as decoration on the front
  - Memorial Court, pre 1906; 489; Color Print
    Caption: 520 - Memorial Chapel and Court, Stanford University, Cal.
  - Memorial Court, 1904; 490; Color Print
    Caption: 8576 - Memorial Court, Leland Stanford Jr. University.
  - Memorial Court, pre 1906; 491; Color Print
    Caption: 52 - Memorial Court and Chapel, Stanford University, Cal.
    Message: Mar. 14/15. Elijah's Faithful God. When the poor and needy seek water, and there is none, and Their tongue faileth for thirst, I the Lord will hear them, I the God of Israel will not (illegible) them. (illegible) 41, 17
    Imprint: I. Scheff & Bros
  - Memorial Court, pre 1906; 492; Color Print
    Caption: 5218 - Memorial Court, Stanford University, Chapel in distance.
  - Memorial Court, Undated; 493; Color Print
    Caption: 2170 - Memorial Court, Stanford University, California
    Imprint: Ewd. H. Mitchell
  - Memorial Court, 1912; 494; Photo
    Caption: Memorial Court, Stanford
    Message: I was very sorry not to see you while I was in Los Angeles for I wanted to tell you much about the glories of Stanford. It is the best place ever -- better than I thought it could be. Of course I'd never try to convince you for I know "a man convinced against his will is of the same opinion still" but just tell you about it. Sincerely, Frances M Hoyt. Stanford University -- Jan. 12, 1912
    addressed to: Mr. Prentice Lebus, 1222 Bonnie Brae, Los Angeles, California
  - Meyer Library, pre 1982; 495; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford University - The J. Henry Meyer Memorial Libary at Stanford University bears the name of an early California businessman. Dedicated in 1966, it has a capacity of 140,000 volumes, arranged in open shelves according to undergraduate subject areas.
    Galvez Street still open to car traffic along side of Library
    Meyer Library
  - Museum, Undated; 496; Photo
    Caption: The Stanford University Museum
  - Museum, 1906; 497; B/W Print
    Caption: 6102 - Museum, Stanford University, Cal.
    Message: 10-13-06 Dear Frieda: -- Arrived here 11:00 instead of 10:16 AM. Went to football game of Freshmen this afternoon. Guess you will go to singing Monday night. With Love -- Amanda & Elsa.
    addressed to: Miss Frieda Thomas, 26 Latona St., San Francisco, California
  - Museum, Undated; 498; B/W Print
    Caption: 578 - Museum, Stanford University, Palo Alto, Cal.
    texturized/embossed
  - Museum, Undated; 499; Sepia Print
    Caption: 47 - Museum, Leland Stanford Jr. University, Palo Alto, California: On the road of a thousand wonders
    Imprint: California Sales Co.
  - Museum, Undated; 500; Color Print
    Caption: 740 - Museum, Stanford University, California
  - Museum, 1911; 501; Photo
    Message: The Museum Building of Stanford University. Dec. 23, 1911. The day before Vacation began yesterday, and yesterday I made some pictures for the first time since leaving home. Reports for the semister [sic] will not be out until Dec. 30th. H. A. Holden.
    addressed to: Mrs. M. Almira Foster, City Hospital, Albany, New York. Nurses' Home
  - Museum, Undated; 502; Photo
    Caption: Museum, Stanford University, Cal.
  - Museum, Undated; 503; Photo
  - Museum, Undated; 504; Photo
  - Museum, Undated; 505; Color Print
    Caption: 1906 - Museum, Stanford University, California
  - Museum, Undated; 506; Color Print
  - Museum, Undated; 507; B/W Print
  - Museum, Undated; 508; Color Print
    Caption: Leland Stanford Jr. Museum, Palo Alto, Cal: The University building are the most beautiful in America. Tuition is free and it is the richest endowed university in the world.
  - Museum, circa 1910-1915; 509; Photo
  - Museum, 1906; 510; Sepia Print
  - Museum and Memorial Church, Undated; 511; Color Print
    Caption: 8631. Stanford University and Memorial Church, Palo Alto, Cal.
  - Museum, Undated; 512; Color Print
    Caption: 1406 Museum, Stanford University, California
  - Museum, Undated; 513; Color Print
    Addressed to: Miss Elsie Riverson, Los Angeles, Cal. 22nd and Vermont, West Office.
  - Museum, Undated; 514; Color Print
    Caption: The Leland Stanford Museum - Located west of Palm Drive, Stanford University, Calif. After being closed for many years, re-opened to the public in 1954. Open daily 1 to 5 p.m., except Tuesday.
    Imprint: B. Frank Thompson
  - Museum, Undated; 515; B/W Print
    Caption: The Outer Quadrangle, Stanford University
    Message: Mosher Estate
    Imprint: H.W. Simkins Publ.
  - Museum, Undated; 516; B/W Print
    Caption: Museum, Stanford University, Cal. 263
    Imprint: Pacific Novelty Co. San Francisco and Los Angeles
  - Museum, Undated; 517; Photo
    Message: Jan 15 - 22 1911. "New Lake." Jan storm y '11.
    Imprint: Robinson and Crandall, Palo Alto, Cal.
  - Old Union, Undated; 518; Color Print
    Caption: PA6:-Stanford Union, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California
    Message: Sept 27 Nice to get your greetings here in Palo Alto. Anne is showing us a wonderful time, and we'll hate to move on in the morning. One of her friends invited us for dinner tomorrow night, but we've got to get back to Orono sometime. Marjorie
    Imprint: Scenic View Card Co., 667 Mission St., San Francisco, Cal.
    Addressed to: Mrs. Fred Buffin, 149 Main St., Orono, Maine.
    Old Union
  - Old Union, Undated; 519; Color Print
    Caption: The Stanford Union, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California. This attractive garden spot and building, centrally located on the Stanford Campus, is a residence for women.
    Message: 7/16/49 Having swell time doing nothing but eating fried chicken and a little swimming. Presperation from my brow. Ethel and Arthur say Hellow. "Lew"
    Front and Back Office Slaves, City Hall, Albany 6, Calif.
  - Old Union, Undated; 520; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford Union...The favorite meeting place for the University students. Houses the Union Store, Dining Room, Union Cellar and Women's Residence.
  - Old Union, Undated; 521; Color Print
    Caption: Stanford University, Palo Alto, California, Home of Student Body Office and center of Stanford Student Activities.
    Imprint: Igor Stchogoleff
  - Old Union, Undated; 522; Color Print
    Caption: Students Union Building, Stanford University, California
    Imprint: Pacific Novelty Co., San Francisco and Los Angeles
  - Old Union, Undated; 523; B/W Print
    Caption: Stanford Union, Stanford University
    Message: 7/ 17.50 Purchased for $14.00 12/79
    Imprint: Bardell Hi-Gloss Print. Pub.
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 524; B/W Print
    Caption: The "Palo Alto" Tree. The Palo Alto [High Tree] stands near the S.F Depot. Palo Alto gets its name from the tree. Palo Alto is a thriving young town of three thousand inhabitants, no saloons, and plenty of churches.
    Palo Alto Tree
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 525; Sepia Print
    Caption: 5075 Palo Alto Tree, Stanford University, California
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 526; Color Print
    Caption: Palo Alto Tree, Stanford University, California
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 527; Photo
    Caption: Palo Alto Tree, Palo Alto, Cal.
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 528; Tinted Print
    Caption: Palo Alto Tree. Palo Alto, Cal.
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 529; B/W Print
    Caption: 7352 Palo Alto Tree, Palo Alto, Cal.
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 530; B/W Print
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 531; Color Print
    Caption: Palo Alto Tree, Stanford University
    Message: How are you and the nieces? I received the letters and thank you. I may be able to call you by this coming Sunday.
    Addressed to: Mrs G.E. Manning, 3677 Clay St., San Francisco, Calif.
    from: M. Matend, 656 Channing Ave., Palo Alto.
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 532; Color Print
    Caption: 433 - Palo Alto Tree, Palo Alto, California
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 533; B/W Print
    Caption: The Palo Alto, Stanford
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 534; Photo
    Caption: No. 11. Palo Alto Tree
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 535; Photo
    Caption: The Palo Alto Tree
    Imprint: Robinson and Crandall
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 536; Sepia Print
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 537; Photo
    Message: Dear Carolyn, - We have moved to 935 Scott St. and have a cozy house or cottage, with furniture of our own. Write and let us know how you all are. Lovingly Fred and Wionna come and visit also.
    Imprint: E. C. Kropp Co.
    Addressed to: Miss Carolyn Brasch, 1059 Burdick St., San Francisco, Cal.
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 538; Photo
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 539; Color Print
    Caption: The "Palo Alto" Tree, Palo Alto, California. Under this Giant Redwood the "Palo Alto" Nov. 6th to 11th, 1769 - camped Portola and his band - the expedition that discovered San Francisco Bay. This was the assembling point for their reconnoitering parties. Other early explorers - De Anza, Vancover also used the tree as a landmark. Earlier, Indians held their council meetings here.
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 540; Color Print
    Caption: 5394 - The Famous Palo Alto Tree, Santa Clara Valley, California
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 541; Color Print
    Caption: Palo Alto California was named after this "Tall Tree" under which the Gaspar de Portola expedition camped November 6 - 11, 1769.
    Message: This redwood tree is on the eastern edge of a ravine that's on the west side of Palo Alto, and is growing just beside, and on the north of the the Southern Pacific Railroad, which runs over a bridge over the ravine. Latitude:- Longitude:-
    (-This tree was on Senator Leland Stanford's "Palo Alto Farm".)
    given to Stanford University Library, 25 July 1955, Monday
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 542; Photo
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 543; Photo
  - Palo Alto Tree, Undated; 544; Sepia Print
    Caption: 1894 - Palo Alto Tree, Palo Alto California
    Message: Mr. Garman, Dear Sir: Since mailing my parcel I ran across these old photograph cards of the Stanford grounds, which are quite old. I will mail them if any one might care for them for their collection. Yours truly, Alma Gunnison. Veterans Home, California.
    Addressed to: Mr. Charles R. Garman, The Stanford University Libraries, Stanford, California.
  - Post Office, Undated; 545; B/W Print
    Caption: No. 37. Post Office, Stanford University, Cal.
    Post office
  - Post Office, Undated; 546; Sepia Print
    Caption: 1913: Post Office, Stanford University, California
  - Outer Quad, Undated; 547; Photo
    Outer Quad
  - History Corner, Undated; 548; Photo
    Caption: History Building. Stanford University, Cal.
    Quad Corners
  - History Corner, with car in front, Undated; 549; Color Print
    Caption: Outer Quadrangle, Stanford University, Cal.
    Message: Does this look familiar to you? Come down and join me and we'll have a sporty time. I went to the "Fly Trap" for dinner last night. Does it appeal to you? yours, A. H. S
    Addressed to: Miss May Crutchlaw, Miller Flats, Salt Lake City, Utah
  - Roble Corner, Undated; 550; Photo
    Caption: Stanford University - The Roble Corner
  - Physics Corner, Undated; 551; Photo
  - Roble Corner, Undated; 552; Photo
    Caption: Roble Corner
  - Roble Corner, Undated; 553; B/W Print
  - Roble Corner, Undated; 554; B/W Print
    Caption: Roble Corner, Stanford University
  - Physics Corner, Undated; 555; Sepia Print
    Caption: 1911- Physics Building, Stanford University, California
  - Geology Corner, Undated; 556; B/W Print
    Caption: Stanford University - The Geology Corner
  - Geology Corner, Undated; 557; B/W Print
  - Humanities Corner, Undated; 558; B/W Print
  - Geology Corner, Undated; 559; Photo
    Message: The Engineering Building of Stanford University. "Happy New Year." Spent mine in San Francisco. Read your Christmas remembrance. Accept thanks. Passed my examinations, but received a low mark in Mathematics.[something] does not begin until Jan. 9th. H. A. Holden
    Addressed to: Mrs. Almira Foster, City Hospital, Albany, New York
  - South East Corner, Undated; 560; Color Print
    Caption: South East View of Stanford University, Cal.